Address: Santa Clara, CA 95050

Phone: (408) 892-4717

Email: arjohnson.se@gmail.com Website: anryjohn.github.io

# Andrew Johnson

# **SUMMARY**

A driven Software Engineer with 5 years professional experience translating business requirements and user stories into code modules and software solutions. Comprehensive top-to-bottom experience with project management and the development lifecycle for web applications and back-end systems.

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### Luther Systems, Los Gatos, CA — Software Engineer

June 2022 - November 2023

- Identified and filled in platform architectural and back-end feature gaps by implementing custom microservices and integrating new technologies.
- Developed and deployed robust RESTful APIs alongside React-based environment iterations to further build out distributed ledger-based asset management platforms, ensuring high performance and scalability.
- Utilized Go and Lisp to implement critical functionalities, including date state versioning, rollback procedures, external library integration, and workflow optimization, enhancing platform robustness and growth potential.
- Optimized both local remote QA and CI/CD pipelines by pinpointing and circumventing bottlenecks, resulting in a 50% increase in testing efficiency and faster product iteration.
- Led and facilitated Agile team meetings, outlining story requirements and driving project progress through implementation roundtable sessions and feature workflow whiteboarding.

# DataCare, San Jose, CA — Software Engineer

October 2018 - May 2022

- Applied HTML, CSS, and PHP proficiency to build several client-facing, configurable modules and services that expedited key user workflows, resulting in 25% faster turnaround in document processing.
- Coupled advanced MySQL and JavaScript expertise to create dynamic queries and data visualizations for comprehensive data management and presentation, empowering both internal teams and clients with actionable insights.
- Accelerated bug resolution, ensuring seamless operation of the platform, and exceeded client onboarding needs by delivering tailor-made features and configurations.
- Presented and recorded thorough project demos to clients, showcasing platform features and securing buy-in for future enhancements.

# **RELEVANT SKILLS & TOOLS USED**

**Languages, Frameworks & Development** - Javascript, Go (Golang), PHP, Python, Lisp, JAVA, C++, MySQL, NoSql, Redis, JQuery, HTML, CSS, React, Django, Node.js, REST APIs, Bootstrap, Tailwind

**Tools & Environments** - Docker, Kubernetes, Postman, Terraform, Azure DevOps, Unix, Git, GitHub, Visual Studio, PhpStorm

Project Management & QA - Agile, Scrum, Confluence, JIRA, Trello, Unit Testing, Code Review

# **EDUCATION**

UC Santa Cruz, Santa Cruz, CA — Computer Science (B.S.)

September 2014 - June 2018